呼啸吧  狂风  吹破你的脸颊
Blow, winds! And crack your cheeks!
骤雨
Rain!
翻涌吧  洪水
Blow... You cataracts
飓风
and hurricanoes,
爆发吧 直至...
spout till you have...
爸爸
Dad.
知道你想问什么  我的答案是肯定的
I know what you're asking, and the answer is yes.
是的  你可以带你祖母
Yes, you can take your grandmother
和她的李尔王剧团跟你一起上大学去
and her entire production of "King Lear" to college with you.
我要发疯了
I'm going crazy.
耳塞
Ear plugs?
那个没用  我得找点事情做
Not that. I need something to do.
照计划我本该在斯坦福
I had planned to be at Stanford,
可如今我只能干等着
but now I'm here, just waiting.
学校的事怎么样了
What about school?
学分都修完了
I finished all my credits.
这学期我要上的唯一一个课程
All I'm taking this semester is...
是理论物理学
theoretical physics.
也许这就是你所需要的
Well, maybe this is exactly what you need
给自己一点时间  发现自我
a little time off to discover yourself
旅行  冒险
travel, adventure.
去积攒一点人生经验吧
Go for a little life experience.
这主意棒极了
That's a great idea.
我可以去实习
I could get an internship.
在工作中获得实践经验
Practical experience in the job market,
试试水温
you know, test the waters.
呃  我其实不是那个意思...
Well, not exactly what I was thinking--
谢谢
Thank you.
呼啸吧  狂风
Blow, wind!
雷暴  烈焰  是我的女儿们
Thunder, fire are my daughters!
女儿们呀
Daughters...
就是把李尔王逼疯的原因
That's why King Lear went mad.
在  你好
Yes, hello?
你来电的时间刚刚好
Your timing was perfect.
今天  我老妈在我家客厅里给三个
My mother was teaching three acting classes today,
表演班上课
in my living room.
等等  她的工作室呢
Wait a minute. What about her studio?
被水淹了  她们本来在练习
Flooded. They were doing
李尔王里的"暴风雨"一幕
The Storm from "King Lear"
然后  水就控制不住了...
and things got... out of hand.
提醒我去查查我的保险
Remind me to check my insurance.
蕾妮  什么情况
Hey, Lanie, what do you got?
劳拉·坎布里奇  二十八岁
This is Laura Cambridge, 28.
交警发现她在那辆车的乘客坐上
Traffic found her in the passenger seat of the car.
死亡原因
Cause of death?
勒死的
She was strangled
死亡时间在昨晚八点到十点之间
between the hours of 8:00 and 10:00 last night.
这道淤青表明她被人用手臂勒住脖子
This bruising here indicates a choke hold.
他大概是从后面抓住她
He probably grabbed her from behind
然后用力压碎了她的舌骨
with enough force to crush her hyoid bone.
他  这么说有目击者了
He? So there was a witness?
没有  但能这么干净利索一招致命
No, but to kill her in one swift move like that,
凶手的体型必定比被害人高大
perp had to be taller and heavier than the victim.
可是没有性侵犯的痕迹
No signs of sexual assault, though.
她是在车里被勒死的吗
Was she strangled in the car?
鉴证组没有发现任何搏斗的痕迹
C.S.U. didn't find any signs of any struggle.
看来她是在死后才被人丢在这里的
Looks like her body was dumped here postmortem.
这是谁的车
Whose car is it?
不是她的
Not hers.
她的身份证显示她不开车
She had a non-driver ID Card.
莱恩正在查车牌  看看能否找到车主
Ryan's running the plates to see if we can find the owner.
包呢
And what about the purse?
被丢在垃圾桶里  但里面还有现金
This was tossed in the dumpster. Still has cash in it.
手机呢
Cell phone?
没发现
Didn't find one.
二十岁的姑娘怎么会没有手机
What girl in her 20s doesn't have a cellphone?
德裔瑞士移民后裔组成的传统 严密的宗教组织
拒绝汽车及电力等现代设施 过著简朴的生活
也许她是个阿米什人
Maybe she's Amish.
我查了这辆轿车的车牌
So I, um, ran those plates off the sedan.
这辆车...
And, uh...
怎么了
What?
是属于市政厅车辆调配中心的
It's from the motor pool at City Hall.
市政厅
City Hall?
最后使用它的是什么人
Who used it last?
市长罗伯特·威尔顿
Mayor Robert Weldon.
得知我们的车被牵涉在这件事里
Uh, we're all still a little stunned to hear that
大家都震惊了
one of our cars was mixed up in this.
相信我  我们会把事情搞清楚的
Trust me. We're gonna get this all sorted out.
那是死者吗
Is that the victim?
是的  劳拉·坎布里奇
Yes. Laura Cambridge.
你认得她吗  市长大人
Do you recognize her, your honor?
我的下属大概会知道的更清楚
My staff would know better,
但我相信她不是我们这个办公室的
but I don't believe she's connected with this office.
很抱歉  我必须的问问你  先生
Sir, I'm sorry to have to ask you this,
昨晚八点到十点之间  你在哪呢
but where were you last night between 8:00 and 10:00 PM?
这位就是纽约市最出色的探长之一吗  里奇
This is one of New York's finest, huh, Ricky?
她是最棒的
She's the best.
你一直都是这么跟我说的
Yeah, so you keep telling me.
昨晚我在一个小型的集资晚宴上
I was at a small fund-raiser last night
大约有五十多人
with about 50 other people.
我会给你一张名单
I'll--I'll get you their names.
好的  非常感谢  那辆车是怎么回事
Yeah, I appreciate that. And what about the car?
那是这次活动中我们办公室用的几辆车之一
It was one of several used by my office for the event.
很显然  我的一名下属
Uh, apparently, one of my staffers
在当晚已经将那辆车报失
reported it stolen later that night.
私下说一句
Off the record?
昨晚跟我一起的那些人
The people I was with last night
是我内部关系圈的一部分
were part of my inner circle.
我们正在组建一个试选委员会
We're forming an exploratory committee
来看看竞选州长的可能性
for a possible run at governor.
但我现在还不想把这件事公布出去
But--but I'm not anxious to make that public yet.
我会尽力
I'll do my best
不把这件事声张出去的
to keep the nature of your business private.
谢谢  我真希望昨晚你也在那  里克
Thanks. I hoped you'd be there, Rick.
昨晚是和阿丽克西斯的巧克力火锅之夜
Fondue night with Alexis,
但我的确寄了张支票过去
but I did send a check.
非常感谢
Thank you for that.
我知道你还有许多疑问  探长
I know that you have a lot more questions, detective.
我的幕僚长布莱恩·谢伊
My chief of staff, Brian Shay,
会回答你余下的问题
will answer anything else you want to know.
-听...听我说  杰克  -我听着呢
- Listen, listen, listen to me, Jack. - I'm listening.
你还在摇摆不定
You're swinging in the wind on this,
但如果你给我在委员会里多弄三票
but you get me three more votes on the council,
我就能送你架直升飞机
and I'll send you a helicopter.
你就是那位探长了  对吧
You're the detective, right?
-是的  -请坐
- Yes. - Have a seat.
乔丹  这里不需要你了
Jordan, we don't need you in on this.
我就让你们自己处理这事吧
You know, I'll--I'll leave you guys to work through this
除非  里克你愿意来看看
unless, Rick, you want to take a look
我们的新图书馆建设方案
at our new library initiative.
万一你想支援支援  可就再好不过了
It wouldn't hurt us to have your endorsement on that.
支援我最爱的纽约市立图书馆吗
For the New York Public Library,
一切都不是问题
my first love? Anything.
我已经帮你干了跑腿的活儿  探长
I've already done your leg work, detective.
报失那辆车的人是伊丽莎白·沃森
The car was checked out by Elizabeth Watson,
我们办公室的高级通信处长
senior director of communication here at the office.
昨晚午夜时分  她离开活动现场时
When she left last night's event around midnight,
发现车不见了
she discovered that it was missing.
这是她的陈述报告
Here's her statement.
恕我冒昧  谢伊先生
With all due respect, Mr. Shay,
警方的调查通常是由警务人员来完成的
police investigations are usually conducted by the police.
是的  但很不幸
Yeah, well, unfortunately,
"二十四小时最新咨询"比你们的动作可快多了
the 24-hour news cycle moves a hell of a lot faster than you do.
在这事被曝出去之前
And I have to get all my ducks in a row
我要确保一切都妥妥当当的
before this thing breaks.
这就是我的工作
It's my job.
我的工作是找出杀害劳拉的凶手
And my job is to find Laura's murderer,
因此你若是不介意的话  尽管你介意
so if you don't mind, and even if you do,
我得亲自再给沃森女士
I'm gonna get my own statement
做一份关于那辆车的陈述报告
from Ms. Watson about that car.
同时  我也需要关于你的下属们
And I'm also gonna need statements
是否认识被害人的陈述报告
from all of your staff as to whether they recognize our victim.
请自便吧
Knock yourself out.
但相信我
But trust me,
你这是在浪费你的时间
you're wasting your time.
我的时间我爱怎么浪费怎么浪费
It's my time to waste.
现在  我得干活去了
Now I got a job to do.
我也一样  我跟你说清楚吧
So do I. Let me be clear.
我把威尔顿市长摆在凡事的第一位
Mayor Weldon is my priority.
我不会允许这事大振他对手们的士气
And I'm not about to let this thing embolden his opponents
并摧毁我们之前的一切努力
and ruin everything that we've built.
他说的有道理
He's right, you know?
这事传出去  市长却没准备好应对措施
This thing gets out, Major's not ready with a response,
定会成为数周的封面故事
that's front-page material for weeks.
不管怎么说  它本就是个劲爆的新闻
It's front-page news either way.
如果他的下属想要把伤害控制在最小
If his staff wants to minimize damage,
他们就该老实呆着  让我好好工作
they'll step back and let me do my job.
老实呆着
Step back?
这帮人可是玩儿政治的
These are politicians.
就算去餐厅点菜
They can't order at a restaurant
也要威逼利诱一番
without two compromises and an ultimatum.
贝克特  来我办公室
Beckett, my office.
你在市政厅查到什么了
What did you find out at City Hall?
通报车被盗的职员
The staffer that reported the car stolen
负有丢车的全责
is accounted for all last night,
市长办公室也没人认识死者
and no one in the Mayor's office seems to recognize our victim.
所以死者和那车之间没有联系吗
So her ties to that vehicle could be purely coincidental?
完全有可能
That's entirely possible.
卡塞尔和市长是好友  对吧
Castle and the Mayor are friends, right?
长官
Sir?
这种调查就像是用液体甘油炸弹耍杂技
These investigations are like juggling wet dynamite.
一失手  你自己也会被炸的面目全非
One misstep, and it'll all blow up in your face.
我自有分寸
I can handle myself.
那就好  探长
Well, that's good, detective,
因为关注此事的人可不止我一个人
because I won't be the only one watching.
怎么了
What was that about?
权术之争
Politics...
还有你和市长的关系
and your connection to the Mayor.
那又如何  我们知道他与此无关
Oh, what does it matter? We know he's not involved.
怎么了
What?
她说得对  你在有意偏袒他
She's right. You are biased.
我偏袒
I'm biased?
你知道盖茨上次选举投谁的票了吗
Do you know who Gates voted for in the last election?
我敢打赌不是威尔顿
Because I'm betting it wasn't Weldon.
埃斯波  车辆调配中心进展如何
Espo, where are we on that motor pool?
已经核实了
Verification.
汽车是5点开走的
Vehicle was checked out at 5:00,
午夜刚过就通报被盗了
reported missing shortly after midnight.
所以是在街上被偷的吗
So it was stolen off the street.
看上去是如此
Looks like.
那就表明  和市政厅扯上关系
Which means, any connection to the City Hall
只是碰巧而已
is entirely coincidental.
莱恩  死者的电话记录如何
Hey, Ryan. What do our victim's phone records show?
有打给市政厅的电话吗
Any phone calls to City Hall?
没有电话记录
No phone calls at all,
劳拉·坎布里奇根本没有手机
Because Laura Cambridge didn't own a cell phone.
她的信用卡也已经半年没用过了
And her credit cards haven't been used in six months.
没手机没信用卡
No cell phone and no credit cards?
她可不像是本世纪的人
It's like she's from another century.
阿米什人这个说法看来十分靠谱啊  老兄
Amish theory's looking pretty good, bro.
要是能那么简单就好了
Be nice if it were that easy.
但我觉得她这事没那么简单
But I think something else was going on with her.
什么意思
What do you mean?
劳拉曾是哈德逊大学的文学教授
Laura was a Professor of Literature at Hudson University.
直到半年前她还是学院的后起之秀
She was a rising star in her department until six months ago.
半年前发生了什么吗
What happened six months ago?
她辞职了  原因不明
She quit for no apparent reason.
据她同事说
According to her colleagues,
她也同他们断绝了联系
she also completely cut ties with them,
注销了手机和信用卡
canceled her cell phone, cut off her credit cards.
为什么
Why?
没人知道  感觉是她出了什么事
No one knows. It's like something happened to her.
之后我能找到的就是
After that, all I could find were paystubs
来自快餐店  洗衣店
for fast-food restaurants, a laundry service,
办公楼清洁公司的薪水支票了
and an office cleaning company.
她好像无法长久地干一份工作
It's like she couldn't keep a job.
她从教授
She went from professor
跳槽到清洁工
to janitor?
这像是《心灵捕手》的反转版本
That's "Good Will Hunting" but in reverse.
也许她的家人能透露点情况
Maybe her family can shed some light.
我查到了她的亲属
Well, I tracked down her next of kin.
她有个姐姐  正在来警局的路上
She has a sister. She's on her way in now.
很好  你们仔细查探一下她的生活
All right, you guys dig in to her life,
看看出事那晚她去了哪里
see if we can find out where she was the night she died.
卡塞尔和我会搜索她的公寓
Castle and I will go over to her apartment
看能否查出她是和谁在一起
to see if we can find out who she was with.
老实说  她不怎么和人交流
Well, honestly, she pretty much kept to herself.
她不拖欠房租  这就够了
She paid on time. That's what matters.
那是我的东西  你拿了我的东西
That's my stuff! You took my stuff!
不像这两个傻瓜
Unlike those two chuckleheads.
不好意思  警官
Uh, excuse me, please, officer,
不好意思  先生
and, uh, gentleman.
安静点  别吵吵
Hey, pipe down, for crying out loud!
"警官与先生"
"Officer and a gentleman."
这可以作为我们罪案博客的名称
That could be the name of our crime blog.
罪案博客
Crime blog?
就像你帮我写警察报告那样吗
The way that you help me write police reports?
我看最后还得靠我自己写吧
Got a feeling I'll be writing that one on my own.
看起来没有打斗的痕迹
Doesn't really seem to be any signs of struggle.
没错  也没有电脑和电视
Yeah, no sign of a tv or computer either.
很奇怪对吧
That's weird, right?
一群拖欠房租的家伙
Bunch of deadbeat tenants in here.
你要是无聊  我可以帮你
You ever get bored, I'm sure I could fill up
再填满几个牢房
a couple of holding cells for you.
哈维先生  你最后看见劳拉是什么时候
Mr. Harvey, when was the last time you saw Laura?
-昨天见过她吗  -白天见过
- Did you see her yesterday? - During the day.
她上夜班  我看到她5点左右去上班
She worked nights. I saw her head to work around 5:00.
你知道她在哪儿上班吗
Do you know where she worked?
付工资的地方呗  我就知道这些
Someplace that paid. That's all I know.
你有看过劳拉带朋友  男朋友吗
Did you ever see Laura with any friends, boyfriends?
没见过
No. Unh-unh.
不过昨晚我看到一个男人从这离开
Uh, but I did see a guy leaving here last night.
什么时候
When was that?
9点半左右
Around 9... 30.
正好吻合晚上8点至10点的死亡时间
Well, that's inside our 8:00 to 10:00 P.M. murder window.
你记得他长什么样吗
Do you remember what he looked like?
6尺高
Uh, 6 feet tall,
白种人  深色头发
caucasian, dark hair.
她从未提过这样的人
She never mentioned anyone like that.
她没有交往对象
She wasn't dating anyone.
谢了
Thank you.
我试着给她介绍对象
I tried to set her up with a few guys,
可她都不感兴趣
but she wasn't interested.
你妹妹和市政厅
Did your sister have
或者本地政治家有什么关系吗
any connection to City Hall or local politics?
不  我想没有
No, I don't think so.
你们姐妹俩关系好吗
Were you and your sister close?
曾经很好
We used to be.
她曾经和我无话不谈
She used to tell me everything.
直到半年前
And then... six months ago,
她不再打电话来
she stopped calling.
她的生活脱离了常轨
She just... dropped out of her life.
放弃了教师职位
She gave up her teaching position,
从上西区的公寓搬到
she moved out of her apartment on the upper west side
那种廉价楼里
into that flophouse.
你知道原因吗
Do you have any idea why?
你最后一次和她联系是什么时候
When was the last time you spoke to her?
三天以前
Three days ago.
我过生日  她打来了电话
She called for my birthday.
用什么打的
From where?
她连电话都没有
She didn't have a phone.
我不知道  可她情绪低落
I don't know, but she was upset.
她说她因为工作上的事
She said she was in trouble
陷入了麻烦
because of something that happened at work.
她提到是什么事了吗
Did she tell you why?
没有  她说太危险了不能告诉我
No. She said it was too dangerous for me to know.
所以劳拉·坎布里奇为了廉租房
So Laura Cambridge left a tenure-track position
和给她带来重重麻烦的神秘夜间工作
at a respected university for some flophouse
辞去了在知名大学的终身教职
and a mysterious night job that got her into so much trouble,
最终惨遭杀害
she ended up murdered.
她到底卷入了什么事呢
What the hell was she mixed up in?
那个从她公寓出来的男人
The man who left her apartment--
如果他是凶手  他是在找她
if he's our killer, he was looking for her.
他很可能去工作的地方找她了
He probably went to her work to find her.
这就表示  不管那是哪里
Which means, wherever that is,
那大概是她生前最后出现的地方
it's probably the last place she was seen alive.
我查到了 我查到她在哪上班了
I got it! I found where she works.
她的银行账户明细显示她最近从一家叫
Her bank statement says she received
D.A.G.的公司收到了存款
recent direct deposits from a D.A.G. Corp.
我还得在全市的商业登记处仔细查找一下
Now I had to dig deep within the city's business registries,
不过我找到了一家D.A.G.公司
but I found one listing for a D.A.G. Corp
在二三大道间的包厘街上
between 2nd and 3rd in the Bowery.
咱们走吧
Let's go.
就是这里  250号套间
There it is. Suite 250.
你觉得这会是什么生意
What kind of business do you think this is--
进出口走私  洗钱
shadowy import/export, money laundering,
血汗工厂
sweatshop?
求求你  不要
No, please.
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
住手  你弄疼我了
Stop it. You're hurting me.
鲍比
Bobby?
快停下
Stop!
停
够了
Stop!
纽约警局  不许...
NYPD, no...
我是个叛逆的女学生
I'm a bad little schoolgirl.
只是间办公室
It's just an office.
仅限女性工作者吗
Where only women work?
宝贝  我还在
Oh, yeah, baby. I'm still here.
这是个什么地方
What is this place?
我说  这里大概4.99美元一分钟
I'd say it's about $4.99 a minute.
肯定不是血汗工厂
It's not a sweatshop.
是一家色情电话公司
It's a sex shop.
莫里  继续  继续  不要停
Oh, Murray. Yeah, yeah. Yeah, like that.
詹姆斯  听到高跟鞋
You hear the clicking of stilettos
向你走来的声音了吗
coming towards you, James?
农田里  四下无人
...farm, no men for miles.
你能留下来...
Could you stay and...
长着利牙的吸血鬼压着你
Vampire with sharp teeth for to hold you down
而我在吮吸你的...
while I suck your...
劳拉是我们这最受欢迎的其中一位
Laura was one of my favorites.
甜美  聪明又有趣的女孩
Just a sweet, intelligent, funny girl.
她才来了几个月
She'd only been here a few months,
已经成为了最受欢迎的女神之一
and already, she was one of our most popular goddesses.
真不敢相信她死了
I can't believe that she's dead.
她昨晚有工作吗
Was she taking calls last night?
没有  她昨晚请假了
No. No, she took last night off.
说有事要处理
Said she had something to take care of.
劳拉和她姐姐说自己工作上遇到了麻烦
Laura told her sister that she was in trouble at work,
发生了一些事
that something had happened.
据我所知什么事都没有
Nothing happened that I know of.
过去几天她是有点心不在焉的
I mean, she did seem distracted the past few days,
但仅此而已
but that's about all.
作为首席
Well, being the chief...
执"性"官
"Sexecutive officer,"
你有发现她和同事之间有什么矛盾吗
did you notice any conflicts with her and her colleagues?
她不爱交际
Well, she kept to herself.
但和其他女孩关系不错
But she got along well with the other girls.
没有针对劳拉的投诉
There were no complaints about Laura.
她有和你说过为什么要在这工作吗
Did she ever tell you why she was working here?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我  我只是觉得奇怪
I-I just find it odd.
她是一名有着大好前途的老师
She's a professor with a promising career ahead of her,
然后突然之间
and then all of the sudden,
她成了一名电话调情工作者
she decides to become a phone sex operator.
可能她就是喜欢呢
Maybe she liked it.
这里形形色色的人都有  探长
We get all types here, detective--
学生  女演员  妈妈们
students, actresses, moms.
一名会计师从事这个职业  因为她想要挑战自己
I knew an accountant who did it because she liked the challenge
而且这让她欲罢不能
and it turned her on.
让客户为你痴狂是件很有成就感的事
It's a powerful thing to make a client lust for you.
有没有可能她的客户迷上了她
Any chance that one of her clients became obsessed with her?
亲爱的  着迷了我们才有收入
Oh, honey, obsession pays our bills.
他们会不会发现了她的真实身份
Could they have found out her real identity,
然后缠上了她
maybe contacted her?
当然不可能
Absolutely not.
不会的  所有的姑娘都是匿名的
No, we keep all of our girls anonymous.
客户们不可能直接找上她们的
Clients can't be contacted directly.
他们都打到总台  所有的电话
They call one central line, and all our calls
被调度员分配到每一个姑娘
are routed to each girl by our dispatcher.
是我负责记录客户的名字
Uh, yeah, it's my job to take the client's name
和信用卡信息
and credit card information,
然后把电话转给姑娘们
and then route the calls to the girls.
现在是下午两点  一直这么忙吗
It's 2:00 in the afternoon. Is it always this busy?
是的
Sure.
有些人需要早起运动
Some guys need a morning jolt,
有些人则需要下午的提神运动
Some guys need an afternoon pick-me-up.
应该有人告诉他们  咖啡更便宜
Someone should told them, coffee's cheaper.
这不仅关乎性爱而已
It's not just about the sex.
这也是大部分人对这个行业的困惑之处
That's the part of this business most people don't understand.
男女都打电话来
Guys call, girls call,
他们寻求释放
they're looking for release.
有时候通过性爱  但有时候
Sometimes that release is sexual, but sometimes--
也是种治疗
It's therapy.
或者  至少我是这么听说的
Or...so I've been told.
这倒是
It's true.
劳拉之所以这么受欢迎
Laura was a successful goddess
不仅凭借她的性感嗓音
not just because of her sexy talk,
更因为她是个很好的倾听者
but because she was a really good listener.
也可能为她招来杀身之祸
Well, that might have gotten her killed.
萨拉  她有要求拒接某个客户的电话吗
Sarah, were there any clients that she asked to have blocked?
没有
No.
工作上的问题呢
What about problems here at work?
她有没有什么瞒着老板的
Was there anything she couldn't tell her boss about?
没有  她...
No. She, um...
她怎么了
She what?
-萨拉  -对不起
- Sarah? - I'm sorry.
天呐  真的很对不起
Oh, god. I'm so sorry.
她的死都是我的错
It's my fault she's dead.
怎么回事
How?
有客户知道她是谁了吗
Did a client find out who she was?
不  恰恰相反
No. It was the other way around.
劳拉大概一周前来找我
Laura came to me about a week ago.
她  她想要一位客户的联系方式
She, um, she wanted a-a client's contact information.
我告诉她那违反了规定
I told her it was completely against policy.
但她一定要
But she was desperate.
说那事性命攸关
She said it was a matter of life and death.
我们想要那位客户的名字
Okay, we're gonna need that client's name.
埃德加·纳瓦罗吗
Edgar Navarro?
我什么都没做
Hey, I didn't do nothing.
你无权在我妈妈面前把我拖出来
You had no right to drag me out in front of my moms.
是嘛  昨晚八点至十点你在哪
No? Where were you last night between 8:00 and 10:00?
问这干嘛
What's this about?
-你认识这个女人吗  -听着  我
- Do you recognize this woman? - Hey, look, I--
我不知道她和你们说了什么
I don't know what she told you,
但我们只是聊天而已
but all we did was talk.
我没做任何违法的事
I didn't do nothin' illegal.
那她怎么死了
Then how come she's dead?
你说什么
W-what?
我们知道她给你打了电话  埃德加
We know that she called you, Edgar,
你们俩还见面了
and that the two of you met up.
事情不是你想的那样  她找我帮忙
It's not what you think. She just needed my help.
找你帮什么忙
What kind of help could you have given her?
我在牢内学会了如何修电脑
I learned how to fix computers in prison.
这也是劳拉给我打电话的原因
That's why Laura called me.
她要我从她硬盘复制一些
She needed me to copy some digital recordings for her
录音文件
from their hard drive,
但她不知道怎么操作
But she didn't know how to rip them.
我告诉她我需要文件扩展名
I told her I needed the file extensions.
她说拿到后用手机给我电话
She said she'd get them and then call me from her cell
教她怎么做
to work her through it--
她没有手机  埃德加
Only she didn't even own a cell, Edgar.
她有的
Yes, she did.
这就是她的号码
That's her number right there.
她告诉你她为什么要复制那些文件吗
Did she tell you why she needed those files copied?
她说在电话里听到了
She said she'd heard something on a call,
一些不该知道的事
something she wasn't supposed to hear...
不好的事
Something bad.
她需要复制一份做证据
She said she needed a copy of it for evidence.
所以劳拉从没提过让她惊惶的
So Laura never mentioned a call that
那个电话吗
upset or concerned her?
一个字都没提过
She never said a word.
她也没有要过录音的副本吗
And she never asked for copies of recordings?
没有  副本都在我这里
No, and I'm the one to ask.
电脑室一直锁着
This computer room is locked up tight,
只有我钥匙
and I'm the only one with a key.
锁被撬开了
The lock's broken.
进来吧
Okay.
硬盘不见了
The hard drive's gone.
上两月的来电记录都在那个硬盘里
All of our calls for the last two months were on that drive.
你最近一次进来是什么时候
When was the last time you were in here?
今天早上  一切还好好的
This morning. Everything was fine.
这肯定是才发生的
This must've just happened.
今天有谁来过办公室吗
Has anyone visited the office today?
有  一个...
Yes, a...
一个煤气公司的人
A man from the gas company.
他说因为施工
He said there was a leak in the building
大楼里有煤气泄漏
because of the construction.
你能描述下他的样子吗
Can you describe him?
大概六英尺高  白人  深色头发
Um, about 6 feet tall, white, dark hair.
和劳拉遇害那晚出现在她公寓的是同一个家伙
Same guy who was at Laura's apartment the night she died?
那录音带上到底有什么
What the hell was on that recording?
不管是什么
Whatever it is...
都值得为之杀人
It's worth killing for.
那个知道了太多的
So how is the case
色情电话女孩的案子怎么样了
of the phone sex gal who knew too much going?
有点阴谋惊悚片的感觉
It's more of a conspiracy thriller,
像是《窃听大阴谋》或是《凶线》
like, uh, "The Conversation" or "Blow Out."
所有人都想得到那录音带和上面的秘密
Everyone wants this recording and the secrets on it.
非常神秘嘛
Oh, very mysterious.
是的  神秘的还不止这些
Yeah, and that's not the only mystery.
为什么一个像劳拉·坎布里奇的女人
Why would a woman like Laura Cambridge,
一位高学历的教授
a highly educated professor,
会突然之间放弃她的生活中的一切
suddenly quit everything and just drop out of her life
去做那些卑贱不起眼的工作
for a series of menial jobs
最后踏入了色情电话的奇妙世界
culminating in the wonderful world of phone sex?
一点都说不通
None of the pieces fit.
是谁打电话给她的
Hmm. Who called her?
我是说  即使没有电话录音
I mean, you must be able to trace the call
你们肯定也可以追踪这个电话的  不是吗
even though you don't have the recording, right?
我们已经传讯劳拉当班时
Well, we have subpoenaed a list of all the incoming calls
所有来电的名单
on Laura's shifts,
但这好比是海底捞针
But that's gonna be like looking for a needle in a needle stack.
你好
Hello.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle...
还记得我吗
do you remember me?
我们之前通过话
I called you before...
讨论过贝克特探长的安全问题
about Detective Beckett's safety.
我记得
I remember.
这一次  卡塞尔先生
Once again, Mr. Castle,
看来我们又要好好谈谈了
it seems that we need to talk.
你确定这就是上次为了
Are you sure it's the same man
贝克特的事打电话来的人
who called you about Beckett?
肯定是他
It's definitely him.
这么说这个年轻女子的死与
Then the death of this young woman
贝克特母亲之间有着什么联系
is somehow connected to Beckett's mother?
肯定是  要不然他为什么打电话过来
It has to be, otherwise why would he call?
他说了什么
What did he say?
他说还有更强大的力量卷入其中
He said that there were greater forces at play,
其中的利害关系比我们想的更深
that more was at stake than we realize.
这一切显然不仅仅关乎色情电话了
Clearly this is not just about phone sex.
不管那天晚上劳拉·坎布里奇无意中听到了什么
Whatever Laura Cambridge overheard that night,
肯定引起了某人的注意  某个大人物
It got someone's attention, someone big.
我不懂的是  他要你对此做些什么
What I don't get is, what are you supposed to do about it?
我不知道
I don't know.
他给了我一个号码
He gave me a number
让我在需要帮助的时候联系他
to contact him if I needed help.
他说我会知道是什么时候的
He said I would know when it was time.
你打算告诉贝克特吗
You plan to tell Beckett?
告诉她什么  嘿  凯特
Tell her what? "Hey, Kate.
我一直在跟一个神秘人通话
I've been taking calls from a shadowy figure
他想让我阻止你继续调查你母亲的谋杀案
who wants to keep you off your mother's murder case
以免你也遭遇不测
so they don't kill you, too"?
恩  好的
Yeah. Okay.
稍等一下
Hold on. Wait.
你说什么
What did you say?
不  我没在吃东西
No, I'm not eating.
谢谢
Thanks.
嘿  你来得正是时候
Hey. You're just in time.
谢谢你
Thank you.
出什么事了吗
What's wrong?
没事
Nothing.
都查到了什么
So what have we got?
蕾妮刚打电话了
Lanie just called.
她说她在死者嘴里和食道中
She said that she found fibers in Laura's mouth
发现了一些纤维
and esophagus.
实验室确认为浅棕色羊绒
The lab I.D.'ed it as light brown cashmere,
极有可能来自凶手外衣的袖子
which was most likely from our killer's coat sleeve.
棕色羊绒
Brown cashmere.
那我们可以将嫌疑犯范围
So we can narrow our suspects down
缩小到为高品味的有钱人
to rich men with impeccable taste.
你是说你自己也有嫌疑了
Are you saying, you're a suspect?
阿丽克西斯是我的不在场证明
Alexis is my alibi.
那个煤气公司员工怎么样了
What about our gas company worker?
想不到吧  他并不在煤气公司工作
Well, surprise--he doesn't work for the gas company.
警员说在致电性感女神办公室里
And uniforms said that there was no forensic evidence
也没找到任何法鉴证据
at the dial-a-goddess office.
但我们从致电性感女神拿到了
But what we did get from dial-a-goddess were
他们冗长的电话记录  大概两百多页
their copious call logs-- about 200 pages worth.
这些女士们非常忙碌
These ladies are busy.
我整个早上都花在这上面了
I've been going through them all morning,
试图把劳拉的电话从里面整理出来
trying to sort Laura's calls from the other girls' lines.
里面有从市长办公室里打出的吗
Are there any calls in there from the mayor's office?
我以为你十分确信
I thought you said you were confident
他与此事无关呢
that he wasn't involved?
我只是想更彻底和公正一点
I'm just trying to be thorough and impartial.
还没发现
Not yet,
但政府部门的不在少数
but the private sector is well-represented.
这里有警察局的  银行的
I got calls from the met, banks,
还有一些有名的证券公司的
several high-profile brokerage houses.
怪不得会经济危机了  是吧
No wonder the economy collapsed, huh?
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
失陪
Excuse me.
你查到什么了
What do you got?
如果这里出现任何
If anything shows up in here
与贝克特枪击案
and it's tied to
或乔安娜·贝克特凶杀案有关的东西
either Beckett's shooting or Johanna Beckett's murder,
你能马上通知我吗
would you tell me right away?
等等  你们认为这和
Wait. You guys think this is connected--
不
No.
不是我们
Not you guys.
贝克特不知情  而且我不想让她知道
Beckett doesn't know, and I don't want her to know.
你为什么认为两者有联系
Why do you think it's connected?
我只是
I just...
我只是想考虑所有的可能性
I just want to cover all my bases.
-好吗  -好的
- Okay?  - Okay.
-谢谢了  -伙计们
- Thanks.  - You guys.
警员在劳拉公寓周围排查的时候
So uniforms canvassing around Laura's apartment
找到了一名出租车司机认出了她
found a cab that recognized her pic.
他说两天前他送她到
He said that two days ago, he dropped her off
市里的哥谭11频道电视台
at the Gotham 11 TV station downtown.
电视台
A television station.
她为什么去电视台
Why would she go to a television station?
她为什么进入色情电话行业
Why would she go into the phone sex business?
她为什么做所有的这些事情
Why would she do any of these things she did?
希望我们能找到答案  但首先
Well, hopefully I'll get some answers, but first,
我追查了埃德加·纳瓦罗给我们的那个手机号
I ran down that cell number we got from Edgar Navarro.
是部预付费手机
It's a pay-as-you-go phone.
劳拉六天前才开始用
Laura just activated it six days ago.
她基本没怎么用过
She's hardly used it.
她打了个电话给埃德加
She made one call to Edgar
她在遇害那天打给了一个代理商[探员]
and another on the day she died to an agent.
联邦探员吗
A federal agent?
不  一个出版商  特雷弗·海因斯
No, a book agent. Trevor Hanes.
实在是太不幸了
It's just absurdly tragic.
劳拉是一位才华横溢的作家
Laura was an incredibly talented writer.
你是她的出版商
You were her agent?
是的  我们是六个月与她签约的
Yeah, we signed her as a client about six months ago
因为她提出了一个很精彩的点子
on the back of an astonishing book proposal.
这本书讲的是什么
What's the book about?
是关于从穷苦大众的角度
It's a scathing indictment of societal inequity
对社会的不平等进行严厉的控诉
as seen through the lens of the working poor.
呈现了当今社会
A sort of contemporary take
底层人们生活困境
on how the other half lives.
一位养尊处优的女性放弃一切
A privileged young woman gives up every comfort
去体验贫困人群的生活
to experience life below the poverty line.
所以她才会做那些工作  第一手资料
That's why she took all those jobs--firsthand research.
这种题材十分卖座
The thing pitches itself really.
我们需要看一下她的手稿
So we'll need to see a copy of that manuscript.
她的调查可能导致了她被害
Her investigations might have led to her death.
她没有手稿  至少我没看到过
Well, there isn't one, at least not that I've seen anyway.
而且我不认为她是因为
Bedsides... I don't think she was killed
反资本主义言论而遇害的
because of her anticapitalist polemic.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
这周早些时候  她打电话到我办公室
Earlier this week, she called my office,
说她发现了一个更为惊人的故事
said she stumbled upon a much more explosive story--
是一桩丑闻  牵扯到一位十分显赫
a scandal involving a very prominent,
在纽约举足轻重的人物
very powerful New Yorker.
她说这会彻底地震动这座城市
She said it would rock the city to its very foundations.
哪个纽约的大人物
W-what--what prominent New Yorker?
她不肯说
She wouldn't say.
我以为她只是想跟我再签本书
I just assumed it was a pitch for her next book.
我们约好这个礼拜讨论的
We were gonna discuss it this week.
对不起  失陪一下
Sorry. Excuse me.
埃斯波
Hey, Espo.
-什么事  -我在哥谭11频道的办公室
- What's up? - I'm at the Gotham 11 Office.
你得过来看看
There's something you need to see.
这位是帕特·麦康诺  劳拉的大学同学
This is Pat McConnell, Laura's college buddy.
把你和我说的复述一遍
Tell 'em what you told me.
我很多年没见过劳拉了
Well, I hadn't seen Laura in years.
几天前她突然打电话给我
So a few days ago, she calls me out of the blue,
说是要看看我们拍的一些原始录像
says she needs to see some raw footage we shot
说是她的研究项目需要
for this research project she's working on.
所以我带她来了这个编辑室
So I set her up at this edit bay.
她一待就是八个小时
She was here for over eight hours.
有段时间她都睡着了
I mean, at one point, she even fell asleep.
我当时过来看过她  发现她眼睛闭着
I came by to check on her, she had her eyes closed.
-什么原始录像  -都是副带
- Raw footage of what? - It's all b-roll
拍摄威尔顿市长的
of Mayor Weldon--
市议会会议  游乐场开业典礼
City council meetings, playground openings,
记者招待会后台录像等等
backstage at a press conference.
关于一位显赫的在纽约举足轻重的人物的丑闻
A scandal about a prominent, powerful New Yorker.
这是她看的最后一段录像
And check out this last tape she was watching.
这是移动图书馆基金会
That's the reading train foundation.
去年我参加了他们的庆功会
I went to their gala last year.
你看屏幕边上的这个女人
Now look at the girl on the side of the screen.
是劳拉
That's Laura.
这不可能  他说他不认识她
That's impossible. He said he didn't know her.
卡塞尔  你看市长的穿着
Castle, look what the mayor is wearing.
浅棕色外套  像羊毛材质的
It's a light brown coat, and it looks like cashmere.
和凶手的衣着一样
That's just the coat that our killer was wearing.
贝克特  我了解这个人
Beckett, I know this man.
我们认识十二年了  他不是杀人犯
I've known him 12 years. He's not a killer.
这点你不知道
You don't know that.
我敢肯定
Yes, I do.
卡塞尔  他对我们撒谎说他不认识死者
Castle, he lied about knowing our victim.
他当时站在她旁边
He was standing next to her.
这不代表他认识她
That doesn't mean he knew her.
你知道他一天之内要见多少人吗
You know how many people he meets in a day?
你想要他记住每个人
Expecting him to remember them all--
就像想要我记住
that's like expecting me to remember
每个来我签售会的人一样
everyone who comes to my book signings.
你偏袒他
You're biased.
你说得太对了  我就是偏袒他
You're damn right, I'm biased.
罗伯特·威尔顿是个好人
Robert Weldon is a good man.
好人也会失足犯错  他可以支配那辆车
Even good men make mistakes. He had access to that car.
他的助手说他离开聚会的时间是晚上九点
His aide said that he left the event at 9:00 p.m.
就在谋杀时间区之内
That's right inside of our kill zone.
好吧  那他有何动机
Fine. What's his motive?
我不知道  至少现在还不知道
I don't know, at least, not yet.
那就给他个机会
Then give him a chance,
因为一旦你对他采取行动
because the minute you move on him,
他的事业就毁于一旦了
his career is over.
有什么新消息
So... what's the latest?
我们查到几条不错的线索
We've got a couple of promising leads.
我希望能尽快找到确凿的证据
I'm hoping to find something concrete soon.
对死者的调查有更多发现吗
Well, anything more on the victim?
能把她和市政厅联系起来吗
Anything connecting her back to City Hall?
还没有
No, not yet.
好吧  探长
All right, detective.
有任何消息  及时通知我
Anything pops, you let me know.
真好  这下我成骗子了
Great. Now I'm a liar.
知道我怎么想吗
You know what I think?
我认为她希望凶手是他
I think she's hoping it's him,
因为只要他下台走人  我也就跟着滚蛋了
because if he's gone, I'm gone.
卡塞尔  你不能把这当做是针对你
Castle, you can't make this one about you.
你去哪
Where are you going?
你说的对  我们必须知道威尔顿的动机
You're right. We have to figure out Weldon's motive.
没有动机  盖茨不会让我
There's no way that Gates is gonna let me
传唤大衣做证物的
subpoena that coat without it.
真的吗  你要这么做
Really, that's your takeaway?
你打算让我怎么办  卡塞尔
What do you want me to do, Castle?
我知道他是你朋友
I know that he's your friend,
但如果他真的杀了那个姑娘  那么抱歉
but I'm sorry, if he killed that girl--
-他没有  -那就让我证实
- He didn't. - Then let me prove it.
莱恩
Ryan?
好的  感谢你的帮助
All right. Thanks for your help.
录像查出线索了吗
Anything else on that video?
还真有
Actually, yeah.
我们第一次瞧见劳拉时  她戴着
When we first saw Laura, she was wearing a volunteer badge
移动图书馆基金会的志愿者徽章
for the reading train foundation.
她是市长那个慈善机构的工作人员
She was on staff at the mayor's charity.
这不能代表他认识她
That doesn't mean he knew her.
莱恩  你跟我来
Ryan, you're with me.
卡塞尔  抱歉  你无法客观办案
Castle, I'm sorry, but you can't be objective on this one,
这案子我得自己查了
so I'm gonna have to pursue it on my own.
我不知道威尔顿市长
No, uh, I don't know if Mayor Weldon
是否认识劳拉·坎布里奇
and Laura Cambridge were acquainted.
我不怎么了解她
I don't know much about her at all.
她在这儿没干多久
She wasn't here very long.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我们大约一周前雇劳拉来当志愿者
Well, we hired Laura as a volunteer about a week ago.
几天以后我们就不得不解雇了她
A few days later, we had to fire her.
为什么
Why?
我们发现她拷贝机密文件
She was caught copying confidential files.
-什么文件  -财务数据
- What kind of files? - Accounting files.
知道她为何对那些资料感兴趣吗
Any idea why she would be interested in those files?
-帕克女士  -这是敏感话题
- Ms. Park? - It's sensitive.
我不该谈论此事
I'm not supposed to talk about it.
帕克女士  一名女子被害了
Ms. Park, a woman was murdered,
我们在找寻原因
and we are trying to figure out why.
你可以在这里和我们交代
You can talk to us here,
也可以跟我们回局里
or we can go downtown.
我们最近发现财务账目有问题
We've recently discovered some discrepancies in our accounts.
-有资金遗失了  -多少资金
- We found there was some money missing. - How much money?
两百三十万美元
$2.3 million.
现在正在进行内部调查
There's an internal investigation going on.
这个调查
This investigation,
和威尔顿市长有关系吗
does it have anything to do with mayor weldon?
谢谢
Thank you.
检察长办公室确认
Attorney General's office confirms
威尔顿市长是调查的嫌疑人
that Mayor Weldon is the subject of the investigation.
这不就是我们在找的动机吗
We were looking for motive, and here it is--
价值两百三十万美元
$2.3 million worth.
威尔顿从自己的慈善机构里私挪资金
Weldon embezzled from his own charity.
肯定是有人在与劳拉通话时
Someone must have told Laura about it
把这事告诉了她
during one of her sessions,
然后她决定深入调查
and she decided to investigate.
她找到了足够证据让市长翻船
When she found enough evidence to expose the mayor,
所以他杀人灭口
he killed her to shut her up.
你打算告诉她吗
You gonna tell her?
必须告诉她
I have to.
这事会毁了威尔顿
This will destroy Weldon, you know?
我知道
Yeah, I know.
等他下了台  她第一件事就是
And when he's gone, the first thing she'll do
让卡塞尔走人
is get rid of Castle.
我知道
I know.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
是的  长官  但一旦我
Yes, sir, but the moment
申请搜查证去获取他的大衣
I file a warrant request for that coat,
就会留下公共记录
it becomes public record.
那又如何
So?
到那时每个人都会知道
So then everyone will know
威尔顿市长是我们的嫌犯
that Mayor Weldon is a person of interest.
他不是吗
Isn't he?
他是  但是...
Yes, but...
如果我错了呢
What if I'm wrong?
这会毁了他的前程
It could ruin his career.
纽约市委我们以重任  去保护市民
We... are tasked by the city of New York to protect its people.
有时候要为这份责任付出代价
Sometimes that task comes with a cost.
我知道自己的绰号是什么  探长
I know what they call me, detective--
"铁娘子盖茨"
"Iron Gates."
我也会听到流言
I hear the whispers.
"她是从内务处来的  她一定恨透了警察"
"She's from I.A. She must hate cops."
事实是
Well, the truth is,
我爱警察
I love cops.
我老爸是名警察
My daddy was a cop.
叔叔们也都是
My uncles were cops.
但是袭击了我做巡警时的搭档的
But the sergeant who assaulted my patrol partner
那个位高权重的警长
under the collar or authority...
又有谁能将他绳之以法呢
Who holds him accountable?
也是我们
We do.
去找市长
Go to the mayor,
叫他自愿把外套交出来
get him to voluntarily surrender his coat
做纤维测试  省去搜查证
for fiber testing without a warrant.
告诉他这是避开媒体的唯一方式
Tell him it's the only way to keep it out of the media.
如果他拒绝
But if he refuses,
你去申请搜查证
you get that warrant
尽到你的职责
and you do your job,
无论代价多高
whatever the cost.
你要去见威尔顿吗
You going to see Weldon?
是的
Yes.
我要跟你一起去  我觉得我能帮上忙
I'd like to come with you. I think I can help.
我不认为你能
I don't think you can.
你的话我都听进去了
Look, I heard what you said.
真的
I did.
我想我会很有帮助
And I think I can be a valuable asset.
我跟他一起玩牌  知道他何时是虚张声势
I play poker with the guy. I can tell when he's bluffing.
那如果我要强行请他配合呢
And what about if I have to force his hand,
你还会帮着我吗
can you be an asset then?
我认为不是他干的
Look, I don't think he did it.
但若真是他  我想知道
But if he did, I want to know.
这样说来  我就是客观的
That makes me objective.
你不需跟他们谈话  这是我的职责
Sir, you don't have to talk to them. It's--it's my job.
没关系  布莱恩  我不需要你来保护我
It's okay, Brian. I don't need you to protect me.
-市长  -我没做任何亏心事
- Sir... - I haven't done anything wrong.
就这样吧
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
市长大人  谢谢你愿与我们谈谈
Your Honor, I appreciate you speaking with us.
似乎我也没别的选择啊
Well, it sounded like I didn't have a choice.
上次谈话时
Well, the last time we spoke,
你说你不认识劳拉·坎布里奇
you said you that you didn't know Laura Cambridge.
是的
That's right.
但照片中  你就站在劳拉旁边
And yet here you are standing next to Laura--
她是移动图书馆的志愿者
a volunteer at reading train.
我之前确实没认出她
I-I didn't recognize her,
但你这么说  我想起来了
but in context, I-I remember her.
这次活动是几天前
This event was a few nights ago.
她想跟我谈谈  但...
She was trying to talk to me, but--
她跟你说过话吗
Did she talk to you?
没有  我被人拉走了
No, I got pulled away.
我要和捐款人聊天
I had donors I had to speak with.
我记得她说  她想跟我谈谈
I remember her saying that she wanted to talk to me,
但当时情况不允许
but circumstances prevented it.
你和劳拉并未说过话
So you and Laura never actually spoke?
-没有  -在电话上也没有吗
- No. - Not even on the phone?
没有  说实话  那晚过后
No, honestly, after that night,
我再没想起过她
I never gave her a second thought.
在这张照片中
You know, in this photo,
你穿着一件浅棕色的羊绒大衣
you're wearing a light brown cashmere coat.
希望你能交给鉴证组做检测
We'd like you to turn it over to C.S.U. for testing.
很抱歉  我不能交给你
Respectfully, I'm going to have to decline.
-为什么  -罗伯特
- Why? - Robert...
把大衣给她  对你只有好处
Give her the coat. It can only be good for you.
我恐怕没法那么做
I'm afraid I can't do that.
为什么
Why?
我与劳拉·坎布里奇的谋杀案
I had nothing to do with Laura Cambridge's murder,
慈善机构的公款挪用
or the theft of money from my charity,
或在过去两天里  其他针对我的任何指控
or anything else I've been accused of
都没有任何关系
in the last 48 hours.
你觉得这些事都是巧合吗
Do you think that any of this is a coincidence?
-罗伯特  -不  你听我说
- Robert... - No, me here, talking to you,
这正是他们所期望发生的情况
this is exactly what they wanted to have happen,
所以回答是不  我不会把大衣交给你
So, no, I will not give you my coat.
肯定有一个针对我的阴谋
Look, there's a conspiracy against me,
我不会自己跳进陷阱中
and I will not voluntarily feed it.
什么阴谋
What conspiracy?
我刚决定参加州长竞选
Don't you think it's funny that all this is happening
就发生这些事  你不觉得可疑吗
the moment I consider running for governor?
里克  我早已习惯与人敌对
Rick, I'm used to having enemies.
但这是一项有计划的行动  目的是拉我下台
But this is an organized effort to destroy me.
眼下  我不会相信任何人
So right now, I don't trust anyone.
他不交出大衣的理由很正当
Well, he has good reason to not turn over his coat.
那是  他有罪
Yes, guilt.
这是个阴谋  就这么不可信吗
A conspiracy. Is it so far-fetched?
也许劳拉发现了  试图警告他
Maybe Laura found out about it and tried to warn him.
也可能她与威尔顿确实聊过
Or maybe she and Weldon did talk.
她以自己的发现质问他
She confronted him with what she knew,
他便把她杀了
and he killed her.
我相信阴谋论
I believe the conspiracy.
我了解威尔顿
I mean, I know Weldon.
威尔顿也了解你
And Weldon knows you.
阴谋  诡计
Conspiracies, intrigue--
这是你的精神食粮
That's your bread and butter.
这正是你会买账的故事
That's exactly the kind of story that you would respond to.
不好意思  你是说他在耍我吗
I'm sorry. Are--are you suggesting he's playing me?
我是说你至少要考虑这种可能性
I am suggesting that you consider the possibility.
我要遵从程序
I have a procedure to follow.
他不愿意主动交出大衣
He didn't provide his coat willingly,
所以我得去申请法院命令
so I'm gonna have to get a court order.
纽约警局为调查贪污和谋杀
Look, once word gets out that the NYPD
而传讯他的衣物
subpoenaed his clothing in connection with...
这消息一旦传出去
embezzlement and murder,
他的职业生涯就完了
that man's career will be over.
若他是无辜的则不会
Not if he's innocent.
你开什么玩笑  凯特  这是政治啊
Are you kidding me? Kate, this is politics.
感觉即是事实
Perception is reality.
真相并不重要
The truth won't matter.
那我要怎么做  里克
What am I supposed to do, Rick?
我不能因对他不方便
I can't just stop being a cop
就不尽作为警察的职责
just because it's inconvenient.
不是  不是  你可以等等
No. No, no, no, just... you can wait.
好吗  先找其他线索
All right? For something else, for another lead.
然后等大衣被销毁吗
For the coat to disappear?
你觉得我不知道这里面的利害关系吗
You don't think I don't know what's at stake here?
你觉得我真想这么做吗
Do you think I actually want to do this?
那就别做
Then don't do it.
我没有选择
I don't have a choice.
我的办公室
My office is cooperating
正全力配合这两项调查
fully with both investigations.
站在这里  我可以充满信心的说
And I stand here with 100% confidence
全面而深入的调查
that a full and thorough investigation
会证明这些指控都是不实的
will reveal that I am completely innocent of any wrongdoing.
你还相信他吗
You still believe him?
相信
I do.
你以前曾在另一个朋友身上
You've been down this road before
碰到同样的事
with a friend.
你曾相信戴米安·韦斯莱
You believed Damian Westlake.
而他正因谋杀在蹲大牢
He's rotting in prison for murder.
戴米安和我是童年玩伴
Damian and I were kids together.
相信他是感情用事
Believing in him was sentiment.
我的经验告诉我  威尔顿是无辜的
My experience tells me, Weldon is innocent.
我的经验告诉我  现在这种情况有什么事
My experience tells me, there's something very wrong
非常的不对劲
with this whole situation.
这样的话
In that case,
也许是时候给朋友打电话了
maybe it's time to phone a friend.
就站那儿吧  卡塞尔先生
Right there, Mr. Castle.
站在那儿就行了
That'll be fine.
你知道威尔顿并不是幕后黑手
You know Weldon's not behind this.
所以你伸出了援手
That's why you offered your help.
关于阴谋  他说对了  不是吗
He's right about the conspiracy, isn't he?
他没说错
He isn't wrong.
我该做什么
So what do I do?
怎么才能帮到他
How do I help him?
仔细听听证据
Listen to the evidence.
就像劳拉做的那样
That's what Laura did.
劳拉与市长的录像
I-I watched the video
我看了快一百遍了
of Laura and the mayor a hundred times.
什么都没有
There's nothing there.
我不是这个意思  卡塞尔先生
That's not what I said, Mr. Castle.
我在这个案子以前见过威尔顿几次
I met Weldon a few times before this.
我喜欢他
I liked him.
点起这把烧身之火的人不是你
You didn't set his house on fire.
确实不是
No.
但我却火上浇油
I just threw gasoline on it.
谢谢你过来
Thanks for coming.
我们上次闹得那么僵  我都不确定你会来
I wasn't sure that you would, given the way we left things.
我不会为尽职尽责而道歉  卡塞尔
I can't apologize for doing my job, Castle.
我也绝不会如此要求
And I would never ask you to.
你叫我来有什么事
So why did you call me here?
我灵光一现
Because I had an epiphany.
一直以来  我们一直在"看"证据
All this time, we've been looking for evidence...
而我们实际上应该去"听"
when we should've been listening instead.
事情开端是劳拉告诉埃德加·纳瓦罗
This all started when Laura told Edgar Navarro
她在电话里听到一些
she heard something on a call,
她不该听到的事情
something she wasn't supposed to hear.
我们作家把这称为"引发事件"
We writers call this "the inciting incident."
不管她在跟谁说  不管她听到什么
Whoever she spoke to, whatever she heard,
是导致她被杀的原因
is what led to her murder.
这有什么帮助呢
Well, what does it matter?
我的意思是  硬盘驱动器被偷
I mean, the hard drive is stolen.
聊天纪录没了
The recording is gone.
我们永远没法知道她在电话中听到了什么
We'll never know what she heard on that call.
对  但我们有可能得知她是从谁那听到的
No, but we might know who she heard it from.
你记得劳拉在哥谭11频道
You remember... how Laura fell asleep
观看那些副带时睡着了吗
watching those b-roll tapes at Gotham 11?
她只是闭上了眼
She was closing her eyes.
她没在看带子  她在听声音
She wasn't watching the tape, she was listening to them.
所以你是说她在辨认来电者的声音
So you're saying she was trying to I.D. our caller's voice?
我让萨拉  女神的接线员
I had Sarah, our Goddess dispatcher,
听听那些副带
listen to those b-roll tapes.
是他  我肯定
It's him. I'm sure of it.
他是劳拉的常客之一
He was one of Laura's regulars.
给她看看是谁
Show her who.
我还能在这呆多久
How much more time can I spend here?
是市长吗
The mayor?
先生  再二十分钟  之后我们得
Another 20 minutes, sir, then we have to
-回办公室开会  -是他
- get back to your office for your meeting with... - That guy.
乔丹·诺里斯
Jordan Norris--
市长幕僚长的副助理
Deputy assistant to the mayor's chief of staff.
诺里斯先生  你曾告诉我们
Mr. Norris, you told us
你不认识劳拉·坎布里奇
that you didn't know Laura Cambridge.
对
That's right.
但你89岁高龄的祖母
And yet your 89-year-old grandmother,
格莱塔·马肯森却认识死者
Greta Markenson did.
根据性爱电话记录
According to the phone sex records,
劳拉收到过多通你祖母的来电
Laura received numerous phone calls from her.
这让可怜的格莱塔显得很是调皮
Which made poor Greta look pretty frisky?
直到我们得知  你一直在她家看房子
Until we realized, you'd been house-sitting at her apartment.
我  我可能时不时会打那种服务电话
I-I may have called that service from time to time,
但我从来不知道对方是谁
but I-I never knew who I was talking to.
我如何得知呢
I mean, how would I?
我们待会会查的
We'll get to that in a minute.
与此同时  我们查了你的通话记录
In the meantime, we checked your phone records,
一个月前你往一部一次性手机发了这条短信
and you sent this text to a burner cell about a month ago.
对很多人来说
Now to most people,
那看上去就是一连串随机的号码
that would look like a series of random numbers.
我们调查发现
So we looked into it.
那是市长威尔顿和他慈善机构的
Those are actually numbers to a bank account
一个银行账户信息
for mayor Weldon and his charity.
而有人能利用此账户
Numbers that someone could've used
陷害市长挪用公款
to make it look like the mayor was embezzling money.
市长信任你
The man who trusted you,
而你却出卖他
and you sold him out.
乔丹  他们给你开了什么条件
So what did they give you, Jordan?
他们承诺给你什么
What'd they promise you?
我以为这只关乎钱财
I-I thought this was just about the money.
我  我不知道  我不知道他们试图毁掉他
I-I didn't know. I didn't know they'd try to destroy him.
当你发现你将背叛你的上司时
And when you found out you'd betrayed the man you work for,
你很备受煎熬  对吗
it ate you up, didn't it?
苦不堪言以致某晚在喝了很多杯龙舌酒后
So much so that one night after too many shots of tequila,
你打电话给劳拉  全盘托出
you called Laura and you let it all spill out.
你不想说的
Oh, you didn't mean to,
但她如此善于倾听
but she was such a good listener.
那是匿名电话  我以为是安全的
It was anonymous. I-I was supposed to be safe.
但你没有  因为她是个作家
But you weren't, because she was a writer,
你给了她绝妙的题材
and you gave her the story of her life.
她追查你  出现在你面前
So she tracked you down. She confronted you.
她要揭发你和你的朋友
She was gonna blow the whistle on you, on your friends.
必须得阻止她
She had to be stopped.
乔丹  我们跟你门卫谈过了
We talked to your doorman, Jordan.
我们知道那晚她去找过你
We know that she visited you that night.
好吧  她是去过我家
Okay. She was there.
但  她只呆了二十分钟就离开了
But... sh-she left after 20 minutes.
我没杀她
I... I didn't kill her.
你没必要
You didn't have to.
你要做的只是打给那个一次性电话
All you had to do was call that same burner phone.
接听者派了一名杀手
And whoever answered sent a man,
一个无名无姓的杀手
a man without a face,
他扼死了劳拉·坎布里奇
who choked the life out of Laura Cambridge.
然后他闯入她家和她工作的地方
And then he broke into her home and her work
销毁她手中所掌握的信息的所有证据
and he destroyed all of the evidence of everything she knew.
乔丹  机主是谁
Whose phone was it, Jordan?
你们不懂
You don't understand.
那些人
These people...
比你们所想的更加危险
They're more dangerous than you know.
你将面临二十年监禁
You are looking at 20 years in prison.
我给你指条明路
I am offering you a way out.
你打电话给谁了
Now who did you call?
我要知道
I want a name.
你打给谁了
Who did you call?
我
I, uh...
说他的名字  乔丹
A name, Jordan.
说吧
Say it.
好吧
Okay.
我打给
The person that I called was--
如果你们不介意的话
If it's all the same to you,
我希望你们不要继续盘问我的当事人
I prefer my client not be asked any more questions.
你的当事人
Your client?
诺里斯先生  我是比尔·莫斯
Mr. Norris, I'm Bill Moss.
从现在开始  没我在场
From now on, please don't speak to anybody
别说任何话
outside of my presence.
我已被聘为你的代表律师
I've been retained to represent you.
谁聘请的
By who?
我们到此为止
We're done here.
看来我们的市长能喘口气  伺机再战了
It seems our mayor will live to fight another day.
正义得到声张
Justice has prevailed.
可劳拉·坎布里奇死得不明不白
Not for Laura Cambridge.
我们会以协助犯罪起诉诺里斯
We charged Mr. Norris with criminal facilitation.
已经很不错了
That's something.
乔丹·诺里斯只是个小兵
Jordan Norris is a pawn.
我要的是幕后操纵者
I want the people controlling him.
凯特  这是场持久战
Oh, it's a long game, Kate.
逐一击破吧
Play it piece by piece.
你为什么还要放弃所有的计划
Then why would you abandon all your plans?
所有控罪都撤销了
You've been cleared of all charges.
就一个杀掉他笔下所有人物的人来说
You know, for someone who kills off all his characters,
你有股奇特的
you have a strange
固执的乐观  但是  不行啊
stubborn streak of optimism in you, but, no.
两年后我不能竞选州长
I can't run for governor in two years,
六年后也不能竞选总统
I can't run for president in six.
我的政治梦想
That dream...
破灭了
is done.
总有些我们能补救的  你是清白的
There's gotta be something we can do. You're innocent.
有点太清白了
A little too innocent.
现在我明白了  背后有股势力
There are people out there-- I realize it now--
他们的权力遍布纽约内外
People who control what goes on in this city and beyond.
我不跟他们同流合污  所以他们把我踢出局
I wouldn't play ball, so they took me out the game.
他们已经做出决定
It's been decided.
我就只能走到这一步
This is as far as I get.
那你现在打算怎么做
So what are you gonna do now?
我
I...
会继续在世上最棒的城市
am going to continue being an outstanding mayor
做个杰出的市长
for the greatest city on earth.
卡塞尔先生  你为何主动联系我
Why did you contact me, Mr. Castle?
案子已经结了
The case is resolved.
结了吗
Resolved?
这算哪门子的结案
How is it resolved?
有人想毁掉这个城市的市长
Someone tried to destroy this city's mayor,
我想知道是谁
and I want to know who.
相信我说的吧  这不关你的事
Trust me when I say, it's not your concern.
如果它牵涉到贝克特和她妈妈的被杀  就关我事
It is if it involves Beckett or her mother's murder.
你是个作家  对个下联吧
You're a writer, finish this sentence--
如果威尔顿被赶下台
If Weldon had been run out of office...
我就得从12分局离开
I'd be gone from the 12th Precinct.
那谁来阻止贝克特调查
And then who'd keep Beckett from looking into things
她不该调查的事情
she shouldn't?
谁保护她远离伤害
Who'd keep her out of harm's way?
所以你这样做是为了保护她
So you did this to protect her?
为什么
Why?
卡塞尔  你下国际象棋吗
You play chess, Mr. Castle?
有时  摆放得当的卒子
There are times when a well-placed pawn
比国王的力量更强大
is more powerful than a king.
有需要我会联系你的
I have your number if I need to reach you.
别找我  卡塞尔先生
You don't reach me, Mr. Castle.
我会找你
I reach you.